<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nguyet Minh Duong</title>
    <description>A twenty year-old who loves to drink milk tea and talk about her life.</description>
    <link>http://mimiduong.me/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://mimiduong.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 17:03:42 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 17:03:42 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Southern California vs Milk Tea (part 1)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As a milk tea connoisseur, the subject of milk tea comes up often in my day to day conversation with others. One of the more opinionated discussion is whether or not &lt;strong&gt;SoCal milk tea is &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; much better than NorCal milk tea.&lt;/strong&gt; I hear this quite often, actually – from those who visited SoCal to those who lived in SoCal. So yeah, needless to say as someone who is addicted to milk tea, I wanted to see if thi seemingly universal opinion was true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So four friends and I rented out a car, and planned a five day trip down to Souther Califorina (with only 3 actual day of being there).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/media/souther_california_vs_milk_tea/socalBoba.png&quot; width=&quot;70%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I apologize for the low quality of the photo. Unfortunately for us, the camera we brought with us broke at the start of our trip and we had to resort to my cell phone as a way to document our adventure in Southern California.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can clearly see in the photograph, we came to Southern California, and explored as many milk tea shops as possible. And after having tasted six different milk tea shops, some more than once, I feel confident enough to make a comparison between NorCal milk tea versus SoCal milk tea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But first, let’s see how all of the milk tea shops I went to stand. &lt;em&gt;I also received inputs from my friends for this review, so a special thank you to all of those in the photo!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here is the list of the milk tea shops we’ve visited:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.halfandhalfteaexpress.com/&quot;&gt;Half &amp;amp; Half&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bobabear.com/&quot;&gt;Boba Bear&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yelp.com/biz/ozero-tea-and-desserts-los-angeles&quot;&gt;Ozero Tea &amp;amp; Desserts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yelp.com/biz/formosa-tea-time-anaheim&quot;&gt;Formosa Tea Time&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.honeyboba.com/&quot;&gt;Honeyboba&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://itsbobatime.com/&quot;&gt;Boba Time&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wow… that’s a lot of milk tea shops for 3 days. I may or may not need to write a part two for this review because that’s literally &lt;em&gt;six&lt;/em&gt; different milk tea shops I have to review. And, of course, I have to decide whether or not Southern California really has the best milk tea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;half--half&quot;&gt;1. Half &amp;amp; Half&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first milk tea shop we went to as soon as we reached Southern California. This place was highly recommended by both my friend’s sister, and by my peers. Right after we unpacked our car, we made way to Ranch 99 and Half &amp;amp; Half.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time we reached Half &amp;amp; Half, the line was out the back door. We had pretty high expectations at this point – I mean if the line started from the front of the shop and goes all the way out to the back of the shop, it has to be good right??&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we ended up ordering &lt;strong&gt;eight&lt;/strong&gt; milk teas. And to be dead honest, I don’t even remember what we all ordered, just the ones that really stood out to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here is a general overall review:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Overall: ★★★★★&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;This place was &lt;strong&gt;great&lt;/strong&gt;. I got the &lt;strong&gt;Jasmine Milk Tea&lt;/strong&gt; three times. If you know what you like, then you will most definitely enjoy your drink. I went here on two different occasions, in two different locations. &lt;strong&gt;Both locations have the same consistancy&lt;/strong&gt;, which is awesome! The milk tea was good, and the boba was the perfect texture, flavor, and chewiness. It was definitely worth the wait. &lt;em&gt;Tip: order over the phone if you don’t have the time, and a lot of people are with you! ($10+ orders only).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;However some of their drinks are very particular, such as the &lt;strong&gt;Taro Milk Tea&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Coffee Milk Tea&lt;/strong&gt;. I can see how the Taro Milk Tea can be good, because it had actual taro pieces inside the drink, but that was just not for me. In addition to this, I felt like both the Taro Milk Tea and Coffee Milk Tea were &lt;strong&gt;too sweet&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Milk Tea: ★★★★☆&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;My &lt;strong&gt;Jasmine Fresh Milk Tea&lt;/strong&gt; was perfect. It was perfect in consistancy, in how much milk was in the drink, and how sweet it was. It had the taste that was exactly at the perfect point where it tasted good – and anymore milk would have made it watery, and anymore sugar would have made it sugar water. So it was quite impressive as to how they made this specific milk tea so perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I also bought a &lt;strong&gt;Coffee Milk Tea&lt;/strong&gt; (as a wild card) at my first time there, and saved it for the next day. My first sip made me cringe – my impression of it was simply just &lt;strong&gt;sugary milk with a taste of coffee&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s coffee milk tea, I am expecting it to be a bit more bitter! Instead, it was even sweeter than my jasmine milk tea and my friend’s brown sugar milk tea! I literally threw away the drink before a quarter of it was drank. It felt too slimy, and sweet for my taste. Needless to say, I was super disappointed on my second drink at Half &amp;amp; Half. But I also recognize that coffee is an off choice in flavor, so I should not hold it against Half &amp;amp; Half too much. Mostly since all of the Jasmine Fresh Milk Tea that I have ordered were good – and I ordered like three of them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Boba: ★★★★★&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I’m super impress with the boba here. I really don’t know what else to say about it. It wasn’t too sweet (both times that I went), so it didn’t over power the tea itself or sweetened the tea more. But the boba was sweet enough so that when you are chewing on it, you taste the honey.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;In addition to this, the boba itself is not too hard or too soft, which is a huge plus because this is the hardest part in making boba good. The texture can completely ruin the drink because I’d spend days dodging the boba itself because I didn’t want to chew it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Consistancy: ★★★★★&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;This is what gets me to come back to the shop over and over again. I went to this chain in two different locations, and have ordered similar drinks both times. The taste stays the same, even if I put in the fridge for the night. The biggest difference was probably the fact that by leaving it in the fridge, the drink was a bit more watery – which is totally my fault. But it was good nonetheless!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Pricing: ★★★★★&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;It’s pretty cheap – I think we bought about five drinks for around $13 dollars? For how good it tastes, it is totally worth the ~$3.25 a cup. The price is pretty normal, many milk tea shops charge around this amount for a cup of milk tea. So it is not much to complain about!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you’re going to Southern California, and you’re craving milk tea. I would recommend you stopping by Half &amp;amp; Half. &lt;strong&gt;It is hands down the best milk tea shop that I tried in Southern California.&lt;/strong&gt; I’m not sure if I can find an equivalent one in Northern California, to be honest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;boba-bear&quot;&gt;2. Boba Bear&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No. Nope. No. Just no. Please no. Oh god no. An exaggeration? &lt;em&gt;Not really…&lt;/em&gt; My friends and I came to an agreement that this place &lt;strong&gt;sucks&lt;/strong&gt;. Like I can’t even come up with any excuses for it. &lt;strong&gt;Straight up just tastes like a slightly better Jasmine Milk Tea from Quickly’s.&lt;/strong&gt; There would actually be no reason why I would &lt;em&gt;ever&lt;/em&gt; come here again. I mean, unless I wanted to get high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginning, I thought it seemed neat (or the idea, at least) because it is a milk tea shop that has a hookah lounge with games for you to entertain yourself. OK, so the idea is pretty unique and interesting, I can see why this could be a place people go to before trying out their milk teas. &lt;strong&gt;However everyone who ordered a drink, except for one person, threw their drinks away (including me) because the drinks were terrible.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is my broken down review:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Overall: ★☆☆☆☆&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Did I mention how my &lt;strong&gt;Jasmine Milk Tea&lt;/strong&gt; tasted like a slightly, &lt;em&gt;just slightly&lt;/em&gt;, better milk tea than Quickly’s? We ordered four Jasmine Milk Tea, and one regular milk tea. So it wasn’t just a fluke for my cup – all of our cups tasted the same, and was just as bad.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;My first impression when I sipped it was the fact that the drink was &lt;strong&gt;thick and slimy&lt;/strong&gt;. OK… this is definitely not how I like my drinks to taste. It was a very heavy drink, almost as if they used whatever kind of creamer &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.philzcoffee.com/&quot;&gt;Philz Coffee&lt;/a&gt; uses for their Iced Mint Mojito Coffee (known to be 120% fat or something like that). And when it finally reached the back of my throat, it just stuck there.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;The only thing they have going for them is the setting they created. The fact that it is unique in the sense that it has a hookah lounge, and a board game room for people to entertain themselves. Oh, and I guess having wifi is a plus. So really the only good thing here, in my opinion, is the fact that you can actually sit down and socialize/hang out with your friends.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Milk Tea: ☆☆☆☆☆&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;No. I wouldn’t even drink it if someone bought the drink for me. Seriously, it is 0 stars for me. The Jasmine Milk Tea just felt so fattening to the point that I could not even finish more than a quarter of it. I ended up throwing it away.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Not only is the texture of the drink heavy, and slimy, it is also &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; too sweet for me. If you have had a Quickly’s Jasmine milk tea before, just imagine the the sweetness level being a little bit higher, and the texture of the drink to be a bit more buttery and less powdery.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It didn’t even taste like tea&lt;/strong&gt;, in any aspect! So they lost the biggest selling point for me.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Boba: ★★★☆☆&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I haven’t mentioned anything about the boba so far in the review – and this is simply because it was just “eh”. It wasn’t anything special, as it did not stand out for being perfect and good. But at the same time, the boba was not terrible.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Sadly, this is the shop’s only plus. And I do not like the actual tapioca balls enough to come here for it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Consistancy: ★★★★★&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Like I mentioned above, four out of five of us got a Jasmine Milk Tea. And we all tried each other’s drink. And it all tasted the same – which is good if you like the drinks here. It seems that regardless of how many orders were placed, they were able to recreate the drink without any problems.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;So if you like the drinks here, well you’re in luck because they’re pretty consistent and will probably not disappoint you. Though a slight disclaimer is that we only went to this shop once, it just so happens four of us got the same drink. I don’t really know how they hold up in day to day comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Pricing: ★☆☆☆☆&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;It was like a $4.50 dollar for a regular sized cup with boba. &lt;strong&gt;What the f***?!&lt;/strong&gt; I’m not going to lie… I was expecting the drink to be pretty good because of how much they charge their drinks. And no, it did not include the price of using the hookah lounge (you have to pay for that separately).&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Jesus… talk about a cut throat price for how bad their milk tea is. Many places I have been to, if a cup of milk tea is over $4, it’s usually because I upgraded to a bigger size (~24 oz) or it is organic/artisan/all-natural. But no. None of this at Boba Bear. Just the pure fact that it has a hookah lounge.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Honestly, I could have gone to Quickly’s and grabbed a drink there and would have been less disappointed. At least at Quickly’s, they wouldn’t have tried to over charge me for a very disappointing cup of milk tea.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yeah… &lt;strong&gt;I do not recommend you coming here.&lt;/strong&gt; There are plenty of other milk tea stores you can go to and play board games at. This place is only “worth” if you want to use their hookah lounge, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After talking about my experience here with one of my friends, she suggested that the reason why the milk tea sucked so much may have been because I didn’t get high. So who knows, if any of y’all happens visit Boba Bear and use their hookah lounge while drinking their milk tea – let me know if it tastes better than what I wrote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ozero-tea--desserts&quot;&gt;3. Ozero Tea &amp;amp; Desserts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK… I messed this one up pretty bad. The drink I usually do my reviews on is with the Jasmine Milk Tea, however in the process of buying five different drinks, I accidentally drank mainly the Brown Sugar Milk Tea. And the Brown Sugar Milk Tea definitely gave me a worse impression initally simply because it does not taste like what I was expecting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Overall: ★★★★☆&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I ordered a Jasmine Milk Tea, as always. However the drink that I drank for the most part was a Brown Sugar Milk Tea – not really my cup of tea. It wasn’t until halfway through the drink did I realize I had been drinking the wrong cup. So needless to say, I was thoroughly disappointed up until that point because the drink did not taste like anything I had ordered (as expected).&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I did not get the experience of ordering and visiting the shop itself because we were in a rush, and just had one person pick up all the drinks. I would say the only downside for this milk tea shop was the fact that the location seemed very sketchy, and a bit out of the way for us personally.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Milk Tea: ★★★★☆&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;The milk tea was good however it did not stand out to me at all. I like it, and I would go there if I was invited to hangout there but it is not a shop I would religiously go to. The drink had a creamy texture, which fills me up – probably because of milk they use. I’m not a huge big fan of a creamy texture because it gets stuck in the back of my throat but luckily this drink’s creamy texture is just right.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;The biggest downfall for me here is how sweet the drink is, mostly if you combine it with their boba. This is a personal preference.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Boba: ★★★★★&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I really don’t have an opinion on this boba. Like I mentioned above, the boba is &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; honey boba – meaning it is actually sweet. At the same time, the boba was not hard or too soft. My only complaint here is that they give too much boba as someone who does not like a lot of boba in their drinks.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Consistancy: N/A&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Unfortunately for this shop, we all got a different drink and it was not exactly good enough for us to make a second trip out of the way to get it. I do not have an idea of how consistant the drink is.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Pricing: ★★★☆☆&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I mean, if you average it out, it isn’t super expensive. However it is only if you enjoy more complicated drinks. However &lt;strong&gt;$4&lt;/strong&gt; for a regular Jasmine Milk Tea. I mean, all of their drinks are the same price so I can’t really complain too much. It’s just sad when you prefer a much simplier drink that &lt;em&gt;shouldn’t&lt;/em&gt; take too much work to make.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall it was a good experience that did not stand out to me. Actually, I think I got this drink when I was super tired so I did not remember much about the drink. But if you’re looking for milk tea around the neighborhood, I wouldn’t dismiss this little shop!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can tell, this review is significantly shorter than the other ones, and I hope that speaks for something. I still have three more milk tea shops to review from SoCal before I let you know my final verdict about whether or not SoCal milk tea is &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; better than NorCal!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://mimiduong.me/review/2016/01/04/southern-california-vs-milk-tea.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mimiduong.me/review/2016/01/04/southern-california-vs-milk-tea.html</guid>
        
        <category>review</category>
        
        <category>milktea</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Goodbye 2015, Hello 2016!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Happy New Years!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year had really been more stressful than I could have ever imagined. I had a lot of ups and downs. I was lost more than a million times on what to do, and where to go. But I suppose that was because I was never really focused on what I am trying to get out of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to change that this year. I need a set of reminders on how I want this new year to be different from the last. This new year should be more of an improvement from the last because I am sick of how it’s been, and I realized that nothing is ever going to change unless I fix it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this is probably my first year in a long time that I have a new year’s goals. I came up with some of these after talking with someone about what I had in mind for the new year. It made me realize that I never really had a guided direction into anything, and maybe having some goals will push me into the right direction this year?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here we go…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Keep up with my blog.&lt;/strong&gt;
I seriously created this website for a blog, and I have not written a single thing since September. I feel like I am just so caught up in my life with all of its technical aspects that I don’t focus on my creativity side anymore. For all of those who don’t know – I used to blog &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; back in high school. So hopefully I can get at least a post a month or even maybe do a challenge to blog every day for 30 days straight!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Cut down on all that milk tea.&lt;/strong&gt; 
Let’s be honest, it really is not that healthy to drink a cup a day. Maybe twice or three times a week would be more reasonable. It’s becoming a really unhealthy habit in my life that I need to cut out. The sugar addiction really is not helping me with anything at this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Keep a personal journal, and write in it everyday.&lt;/strong&gt;
I really enjoyed writing in the past, as I’ve mentioned before about my daily blog posts in high school. Unfortunately every year since the start of college, I made up excuses to not write in it because I was &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; busy. This semester will be my lightest semester, so I should be able to keep this goal, even if it’s only 200 words a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Be more social!&lt;/strong&gt;
What I’ve noticed over the past few years in college is that I have became less and less social. As in I no longer go out of my way to talk to strangers anymore because I’ve became a lot more shy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This seems a lot for my goals this year, and I don’t expect myself to accomplish every single one gracefully. However I hope that by December 31, 2016, I can say that I have accomplished at least one of these goals. Wish me luck, and let me know what goal(s) you have for the new year!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://mimiduong.me/blog,%20reflection,%20goals/2015/12/31/happy-new-years.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mimiduong.me/blog,%20reflection,%20goals/2015/12/31/happy-new-years.html</guid>
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>reflection</category>
        
        
        <category>blog, reflection, goals</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Shengkee, the Source of My Addiction</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Many people who know me now know that I have an addiction to milk tea. My addiciton might just be worse than those who requires a cup of coffee in the morning to start working. They know this fact because I have gotten a peak of five cups a day within the past year, and a low of one. Though if I am honest with myself, ever since the semester has started, I’ve averaged around two cups a day. While this amount is about how much a regular coffee addict drinks, the cost is insane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/media/addictions/bobacups.jpg&quot; width=&quot;70%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it wasn’t always like this… I actually rarely ever got milk tea when I was in high school. I didn’t even have my first sip of milk tea until my &lt;em&gt;sophomore year of high school&lt;/em&gt; while majority of my peers are already familiar with the taste of the drink and the texture of the tapioca balls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In high school, milk tea was a rare occasion. This is mostly because there weren’t many milk tea shops around the area where I lived and went to school. If my friends and I wanted to get milk tea, we would have to travel for about fifteen to twenty minutes by foot, up and down San Francisco’s hills – and all of this trouble for milk tea that I now consider to be “low tier.” If we wanted better drinks, the travel time would have been forty five to an hour by bus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So obviously, milk tea was out of the picture for most of our after school activities. Instead, we opt to “study” for our classes and “work” on our homework at a nearby coffee shop called &lt;a href=&quot;http://mamasf.com/&quot;&gt;Mama’s Art Café&lt;/a&gt; instead. And that was where I spent most of my time and money in high school. Not on milk tea but on an ice Chai Latte (often with whip cream on top), with a vegetarian bagel on the side. I was a hipster before hipster was a thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then all good things have to come to an end, and I graduated from high school. That means I have to find another place to fulfill the emptiness in my day once I arrived to UC Berkeley. Which, by the way, was actually the summer before my freshman year because I had to take mandatory summer classes. Like actually mandatory because those who accepted me wanted to make sure I didn’t totally fail out of UC Berkeley. So here’s the solution they gave me: take summer school classes, and if I failed, I can’t attend UC Berkeley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uh OK. Pretty much I risked going to college (in general) for UC Berkeley because I wouldn’t have SIR’d to other schools. All is good though – I ended up passing with flying colors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is where the addiction started….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;berkeleys-summer-is-blazing-hot&quot;&gt;Berkeley’s summer is blazing hot.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s actually a lot hotter than I anticipated it to be. So to cool down, here are the options I am given: Peet’s Coffee, Starbucks, ShengKee Bakery’s milk tea, and a smoothie at the Golden Bear Café. While every single option is great, a smoothie is too cold and icy for me, along with a frappuccino and javiva.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in all honesty, all of the previously mentioned options are too sweet for me and ended up crashing me more than it helped me stay awake – which was something I desperately needed over the summer. I mean, after all, I needed to pass all of these classes. So I begin my search for the perfect drink to keep me alive while I type out paragraphs after paragraphs of analysis on Chicano Studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the first week, my friend (let’s call him Ryan) and I decided to go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shengkee.com/en/index.aspx&quot;&gt;ShengKee Bakery&lt;/a&gt; because Ryan was persistent on buying some Asian pastries. So yeah, we did not initially start going there for the milk tea but rather for pastries that reminded us of home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while we were at it, we spied the menu which sold a &lt;strong&gt;chubby&lt;/strong&gt; cup of milk tea for $2.99 – and toppings are free!! For two cheap, Asian, and college students, this was a &lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt; deal. As a result, Ryan and I picked our drinks. Tiger Milk Tea with boba for Ryan, and Jasmine Milk Tea with boba for me. I had the Jasmine Milk Tea specially made because at the time, they did not have it. Instead they had Jasmine Tea, and ended up mixing it with the regular half and half.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first sip was &lt;em&gt;amazing&lt;/em&gt;. I don’t think I can describe you how all of my senses felt when I took the first sip of the iced cold tea mixed with half and half, boba balls, and sugar. I chugged the first cup I got. I don’t think (up to that point) that I have ever tasted soft and chewy boba balls, and a Jasmine Milk Tea that was in such a perfect consistency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ryan and I enjoyed our diabetes sized drink as we walked back to our dorm to continue our readings on Chicano Studies. And for once, I did not feel the need to take a quick nap to keep myself awake – the milk tea had enough caffeine to keep me cracked out to go through over 50 pages text!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, we just ended up buying a cup whenever we felt as though our energy was low. The trip down to Shengkee and back up to our dorm served initially as a break. A break with a sweet taste. Of course we both didn’t know how big of a problem this will spiral into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the third week of the program, two week after we discovered this amazing crack called ShengKee Bakery’s milk tea, we were known as the regulars there by an amazing cashier named Marie. Every time we walked into the store while she’s working, she already knew what we were going to buy. A Tiger Milk Tea with boba for Ryan, and a Jasmine Milk Tea with boba for me! Marie often teases us about our consistency and our loyalty to ShengKee Bakery. And of course, she made a comment about how we were addicted to our drinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn’t admit to it at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came the deal the turned what seemed to be a harmless routine into an addiction I can’t escape:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;buy-2-chubby-cups-for-499&quot;&gt;Buy 2 Chubby Cups for $4.99&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Oh god, I can’t even tell you how excited Ryan and I were when we saw this deal. Now if one of us wanted milk tea, &lt;em&gt;both of us has to get it&lt;/em&gt;. Essentially we were each other’s enablers. At this point, because the deal was provoking us, pressuring us to make a good use out of it, we kept buying the drinks to get the deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, for weeks and weeks, we repeatedly run to Shengkee in the afternoon (as they don’t serve milk tea until 10am – by then we were already in classes until the afternoon) to buy our daily cup of milk tea. This deal lasted through the entire summer. Honestly, we thought we would have gotten sick of milk tea after a week or so of daily intake. This wasn’t the case… instead, as midterm (and essay writing) season rolled around, we started staying up until 3am or 4am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guess what we used instead of coffee to stay awake? &lt;em&gt;Milk tea.&lt;/em&gt; As a reward for ourselves, and a source of caffeine to keep ourselves awake, before Shengkee Bakery closed (11pm on weekdays, and 12am on weekends), we ran to purchase our drinks. Before we know it, we got two milk teas a day. These cups were 25oz each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drinking milk tea became a very consistent part of my life. I needed it – I spent too much time with it and I can no longer escape from it. By training myself to become more effective with the addictive drink by my side, I can’t focus and work without it. It becomes a need to be productive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks, Ryan, you are an enabler who got me addicted to milk tea. And you’re welcome for the addiction.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you &lt;a href=&quot;flickr.com/photos/cathleenjia/&quot;&gt;Cathleen Jia&lt;/a&gt; for providing the photo!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://mimiduong.me/boba,%20story/2015/09/21/shengkee-source-addiction.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mimiduong.me/boba,%20story/2015/09/21/shengkee-source-addiction.html</guid>
        
        <category>milktea</category>
        
        <category>story</category>
        
        
        <category>boba, story</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This Blog &amp; Me</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my &lt;a href=&quot;http://waitbutwhy.com/2013/10/why-procrastinators-procrastinate.html&quot;&gt;dark playground&lt;/a&gt;! I will be spending my “&lt;em&gt;spare&lt;/em&gt;” time writing up posts that appear relevant to me and my life in the moment. Notice how I put spare in quotes – meaning that I will probably be writing these posts when I shouldn’t be. Oops. At least I can admit it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t worry, I’m a &lt;em&gt;professional&lt;/em&gt; (notice the sarcasm). I have had a long history in relation to blogs, which I will talk about later on in this post. But for now, I want to warn you about my blogging habits: my goal is to post &lt;strong&gt;an average of twice a month&lt;/strong&gt;. You may see an influx of posts in the beginning of the school year, and see me die down as the academic semester because I will be swamped with work and procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I apologize in advance, this will be one of my longer posts :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/media/this_blog_and_me/img.png&quot; width=&quot;70%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I figure if you are reading this post, you are curious as to my goals, intentions, and topic for this blog. Unless I never update my blog and this remains as my only post. (I really hope that doesn’t happen.) So to make it easier on you, I broke down this topic into sections so it can be easily navigated. This post is primarily about my blog, and less about me. &lt;a href=&quot;/about/&quot;&gt;Click here if you want to read more about me!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-blogging-history&quot;&gt;My Blogging History&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not my first time blogging – maybe my first time blogging “professionally” (whatever that means) – but in the past, I have kept a personal blog where I would post &lt;em&gt;religiously&lt;/em&gt;. I’m talking about an average of &lt;strong&gt;1.25 posts a day&lt;/strong&gt;, focusing on daily reflections. However this only lasted for about a year (my Freshman and beginning of Sophomore year of high school). I stopped completely by the end of my Junior year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Owning a blog and a website have been my goal for quite a long time. “A long time” is an understatement. I wanted to have my own blog and site way before 2009 (I have concrete proof in 2009 through my ridiculous Facebook post). But six/seven years later, I am able to fulfill my goal in having my own website with a blog hosted on it. I’m quite proud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-goals-for-my-blog&quot;&gt;My Goals for My Blog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want this blog to hold some resemblance to the blogs I’ve always wanted to have when I was younger. Including having some similarities to my personal blog I had back in high school. This means that at the end of my journey (hopefully never!), I want this blog to be &lt;strong&gt;a form of reflection&lt;/strong&gt; for myself (and maybe others) in the years to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, I want to have fun with my blog. This blog is meant to be a part of who I am and what are important to my life at the moment, as I have mentioned before. Which brings me to talk about the next topic….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-direction-in-blogging&quot;&gt;My Direction in Blogging&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time I write something on this blog, I want it to document a part of my life. So as I have mentioned in the beginning, the posts in this blog will be relevant to events and situations that are happening to me in real life, around the time I post up my posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it just so happen, as you will read, I am currently battling an addiction to milk tea. It is a huge part of my life – I probably averaged a cup a day since the summer before my freshman year of college (Summer 2013) up until the beginning of this summer (Summer 2015). That’s a solid &lt;em&gt;two years&lt;/em&gt;. So definitely expect a lot of posts about milk tea and my expertise on this subject!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though being addicted to milk tea &lt;em&gt;isn’t the only thing&lt;/em&gt; I have going on in my life. I am currently trying to figure out my goals in college and in life. So by writing about them and my attempts to achieve these goals, I will have a reminder of the success and challenges I’ve faced. And in my perspective, these will remind me of my motivation when I fall. And hopefully, people (specifically incoming college freshmen and high school students – more on this later) will be able to use my experiences as a guide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And honestly, I love to talk so this is for my friends who are just &lt;em&gt;sooooooo sick&lt;/em&gt; of me opening my mouth. Just kidding, I love every single one of them. They are the reasons I am the person who I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-target-audience-single&quot;&gt;My Target Audience (SINGLE)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her name is Isabella Marie Swan. She is a senior in high school, and an incoming Freshman in Dartmouth. At the moment, she is blind to what her life will when she leaves Forks, Washington for college. And to be honest, she has a bit of an addiction or obsession.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a hobby, she spends a lot of time reading. Isabella tends to keep to herself at most times but enjoys looking up materials she wishes to know more about. I guess you can call her &lt;em&gt;Curious &lt;strike&gt;George&lt;/strike&gt; Isabella&lt;/em&gt;. It has actually have gotten her into a lot of trouble in the past, including breaking her heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Props to you if you understood this reference. If you didn’t, I’ll credit it at the end of this post.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pretty much copied this out of my notebook. Not word for word but you get the point. This is me using what I’ve learned this summer to create content with someone specific in mind. And in doing so, hopefully I can make my content more focused. Though I wouldn’t be surprise if my friends (who honestly don’t fit the target audience description whatsoever) read my posts and then bring it up to me in person to watch me cringe at my own writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to write and I want to inspire. And if you happened to think this post was way too long for you to endure. Here is my response: same. So here is my tl;dr (too long; didn’t read) summary:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This blog is a reflection&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I will be talking about whatever is happening in my life. So at the moment, these things are: milk tea, and college career choices&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I want high schoolers and incoming college students to read my blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in case you are seriously wondering the reference, the reference is to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twilight_(series)&quot;&gt;Twilight&lt;/a&gt;. Specifically the main character in her point of view during &lt;em&gt;New Moon&lt;/em&gt;. But this doesn’t mean, my possible audience is &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; Bella. It’s supposed to be a joke – no insults, I swear. But I hope you can see the key characteristics I’m trying to go off of and ignore the silly ones!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://mimiduong.me/site-management/2015/07/31/this-blog-and-me.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mimiduong.me/site-management/2015/07/31/this-blog-and-me.html</guid>
        
        <category>updates</category>
        
        
        <category>site-management</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
